

Alejandro Joel Ferrán Pérez

Software Engineer

PROFILE

Software developer with a Telecommunication and Electronics engineering degree. Proficiency in programming languages as Python, JavaScript, C/C++, and others. Network Manager and Web Developer with two years of experience. Work with agile software development methodologies such as SCRUM and Kanban. Involved in developing my skills as a programmer and open to learn new technologies. Interested to join agile teams, where I can learn from my partners and contribute to its growth.

EDUCATION

TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEER

Technological University of Havana "José A. Echeverría" 2017-2021

LANGUAGES

SPANISH - Native ENGLISH - Medium

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

RestAPI **PostgresSQL** C/C++ Django Docker Python Vue (Vuex) Linux

Javascript/ES6 Git Git-flow and GitHub

SOCIAL SKILLS

Telecomunications Network Manager Web Development (Front-end and Back-end) Collective property **Analysis Capacity Adaptability** Time management through tools like Notion **SOLID** principles DDD



PHONE +53 53928565



aferranperez@gmail.com



LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandro-j-ferrán-pérez-0685b019a/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

3/2021 - 2/2022 **Cuban Web Solutions**

 Full-Stack development of new features and maintenance on different websites. The technological stack used was MongoDB, Vue, Laravel, Docker, Bootstrap and Firebase.

Web Developer

4/2020 - 1/2021

Freelancer

- Development of Duartestaxes web portal, where we worked with Jquery, Bootstrap and PHP technologies. Design and implementatiton of a business blog with self-management capacity.

Student

2017 - 2021 Technological University of Havana "José A. Echeverría"

- Integration to an HPC Laboratory, where algorithms related to Machine Learning, Big Data, Deep Learning and Computational VIsion were implemented.
- Design and implementation of an access control system based on facial recognition on an IoT ecosystem. Using technologies such as MQTT, OpenCV, Django, Mosquitto Server and JSON.

CERTIFICATIONS

- SCRUM Fundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)- Certiprof
- Python (Basic) HackerRank
- Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- Remote Work and Virtual Collaboration Professional Certiprof